sendthisfile.com 2017-03-20

# Privacy Policy | SendThisFile

Last Updated: September 22, 2016 

This privacy policy (the "Statement") covers SendThisFile, Inc's ("SendThisFile," "us," or "our") SendThisFile file transfer service website, sendthisfile.com. By using the SendThisFile website, you consent to the data practices described in this Statement, as the same may be updated from time to time. 

### Scope

This Statement covers SendThisFile's treatment of personally identified information that we collect when you are on the SendThisFile website, and when you use our services. This Statement also covers our treatment of any personally identified information that our business partners share with us. 

This Statement does not apply to the practices of companies that SendThisFile does not own or control, or to individuals that SendThisFile does not employ or manage, including operators of websites to which you may link from the SendThisFile website. This Statement also does not apply to any offline collection of personally identified information, or the treatment of the same when such information is collected outside of the SendThisFile website. 

### What information do we gather?

The only individually identified information that we collect about you is that which you choose to share with us during registration, when using our products and services, or when responding to offers from SendThisFile or from our business partners. 

This information includes: 

  * **Email address** : See "Email Communications" below
  * **Billing information**
    * First and last name: Used for credit card processing
    * Business name: Used for credit card processing
    * Street, City, State, Zip, Country: Used for credit card processing
    * Credit card number and expiration: Used for credit card processing

We also collect information about aggregate site usage. Statistics that we gather about unique visits, referring URLs, repeat visits and page views are all based on IP address, and are not associated with your personal information.

### Why do we ask for personal information about you?

In order to use the SendThisFile service, users must set up individual accounts. This requires the completion of a registration form. This information is used to identify the specific individual utilizing the SendThisFile service. Users may provide optional identifying information, demographic information, and unique identifiers to enable us to provide a more personalized experience on the site.

We share aggregate information (information that is not specifically identified to you) with our partners and advertisers. We will not share your personally identified information with any third party, unless we tell you otherwise when we collect the information, you have consented by "opting in" to being contacted by SendThisFile, its third party partners or advertisers, or we have informed you of a change to our Statement so that you can then choose to opt out. We will give you a way to "opt out" of being contacted by SendThisFile.

In short, the information you provide us can help us to understand how to make our website more convenient and useful to our audience.

We also collect information about aggregate website usage. Statistics that we gather about unique visits, repeat visits and page views are all based on IP address, not on your individual activities.

The information we gather is supplemented with information provided by third party sources, and may be used to derive additional data to enhance our databases. For example, zip code information you provide may be used to derive city and state information or may be used to add demographics data.

### How do you update the information you provided during registration?

You have the right to access, update and correct the personally identified information you shared with us during registration. In order to do so, sign into your member account on the website using your member ID and password. Once signed in, click on the "my account" link, and follow the steps to edit your member information and to confirm your changes 

An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct his query to . If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe 

### Email Communications

Periodically, we will use your provided email address for the following:

  1. To send you System Alert Messages to let you know about temporary or permanent changes to our Services including planned outages, new features offered, feature updates, point releases, major releases, abuse warnings, changes to our Privacy Policy and possibly other documents and agreements. 
  2. To communicate with you concerning your account for an informational, as opposed to promotional, purpose. 
  3. To send you informational and promotional materials that you elect ("opt-in") to receive. 

Our email marketing is permission based. If you received a mailing from us, our records indicate that (a) you have expressly shared this address for the purpose of receiving information in the future ("opt-in"), or (b) you have registered or purchased or otherwise have an existing relationship with us.

Unsubscribing - You can unsubscribe or change your subscription to our marketing emails at any time. Simply click the unsubscribe link that appears at the bottom of your email to modify your subscriptions online. 

### Third Parties

We do not share personally identified information with anyone, unless we need to do so to provide services to you (e.g., sending credit card information to a credit card processor), we tell you otherwise when we collect the information, you "opt in" to having your information shared with third parties, or we have informed you of a change to this Statement so that you can then choose to opt out. Additionally, we may disclose personally identified information with third parties if (1) we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to comply with a lawful request by public authorities, including meeting national security, law enforcement requirements or to exercise our legal rights (including, without limitation, a violation of the SendThisFile website _Terms of Use_ or other agreement between SendThisFile and you), or to defend against legal claims; (2) we have a good faith belief that access, preservation, or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our users, or the public, including disclosure of criminal activity or the violation of the rights of others; or (3) if all or a portion of a business of SendThisFile is transferred in connection with a sale, merger, transfer, exchange, or other disposition (whether assets, stock, or otherwise). 

In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield, SendThisFile, Inc. is potentially liable. 

Except as stated above, when we ask you for personally identified information, we will tell you if we intend to share it with others. We will provide you with a way to tell us that you don't want us to share the information or if you don't want to receive promotional and/or marketing information about products, services, and offerings from SendThisFile and/or any third parties. We will also provide you with a way to update your personally identified information that you share with us during registration. Once you have "opted in" and agreed that your information may be shared with third parties or you have responded to an offer by any third party on the SendThisFile websites, SendThisFile can no longer update any of your personally identified information that has been transferred to such third parties or opt you out of such third parties so that you no longer receive their promotional and/or marketing information. Instead, you must either contact that third party or refer to their privacy policy to update your personally identified information or to let them know that you no longer want to receive promotional and/or marketing information about their products, services, or offerings. The privacy policies and practices of these third parties may differ from this Statement. You may not opt-out of the uses stated above or our internal uses of your personally identified information.

SendThisFile may, from time-to-time use the names of businesses that have accounts with SendThisFile in SendThisFile's marketing or advertising materials, in order to show prospective customers the types of businesses that have accounts with SendThisFile. If you do not want SendThisFile to use your company name in this manner, send an email to  and so state. We will send you a confirmation email. Make sure that you receive the confirmation email so as to assure that the transaction was completed.

### How does SendThisFile use cookies?

SendThisFile uses cookies to facilitate the login process for you across multiple applications on our websites. Everything we learn from your activity will be used to enrich your experience on our websites. It will help us understand what you like and don't like, so we can focus our energies more effectively and provide you with better service. There are two types of cookies that we use.

The first type of cookie has no personal information attached to it and is used to count unique users. That cookie can also be used for advertising purposes by SendThisFile, its business partners and advertisers, for serving and delivering advertising campaigns to control frequency of exposure, or to target by domain name, time zone or geographic location.

For any user who subsequently registers with our site, we replace the first type of cookie with a user identified cookie, which we continue to use for unique user counting as well as advertising targeting, but that cookie may now also include personally identified information. This cookie allows you to access all of your personalized areas of the website without having to log on multiple times.

Lastly, there may be a third party cookie in SendThisFile emails that is generated by our business partners or advertisers when they sponsor emails to promote their products and services.

### Changes to the SendThisFile Privacy Policy

SendThisFile may amend this Statement from time to time. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information we will notify you by posting a prominent notice in this Statement or in other locations on our website or by sending you an email to inform you of an updated Statement, at our choice. We encourage you to periodically review this Statement to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the SendThisFile website constitutes your agreement to this Statement and any changes to it.

### EU-US Privacy Shield

SendThisFile, Inc. complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. SendThisFile, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, SendThisFile, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact SendThisFile, Inc. at: 

SendThisFile, Inc.   
Attn: EU-US Privacy Shield Complaints   
2250 N. Rock Rd. Ste. 118-136   
Wichita, KS 67226-2331 

Fax: 316-925-5261, Attn: EU-US Privacy Shield Complaints 

SendThisFile, Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). 

SendThisFile, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/> for more information and to file a complaint. 

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel. 

###  How can you contact SendThisFile with Questions? 

If you have questions regarding the SendThisFile Privacy Policy, you can contact us via email at , or via phone at 1-855-SEND-THIS (736-3844).
